metrocu.org 2019-05-28

# 

                                                                             PRIVACY NOTICE
  FACTS                            WHAT DOES METRO CREDIT UNION DO WITH YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION?
                                   Financial companies choose how they share your personal information. Federal law
                                   gives consumers the right to limit some but not all sharing. Federal law also requires us
  Why?                             to tell you how we collect, share, and protect your personal information. Please read this
                                   notice carefully to understand what we do.
                                   The types of personal information we collect and share depend on the product or service
                                   you have with us. This information can include:
                                         •   Social Security number and employment information
                                         •   Account balances and payment history
  What?                                  •   Account transactions and checking account information
                                         •   Credit scores
                                   When you are no longer our member, we continue to share your information as
                                   described in this notice.
                                   All financial companies need to share members’ personal information to run their
                                   everyday business. In the section below, we list the reasons financial companies can
  How?                             share their members’ personal information; the reasons Metro Credit Union chooses to
                                   share; and whether you can limit this sharing.
  Questions:                       Contact our Member Service Center, 877-MY-METRO (877-696-3876)
                                                                                   Does Metro Credit      Can you limit this
            Reasons we can share your personal information
                                                                                     Union share?              sharing?
  For our everyday business purposes –
  Such as, to enable us to process your transactions, maintain your account(s),          Yes                      No
  respond to court orders and legal investigations, or report to credit bureaus.
  For our marketing purposes –                                                            Yes                     No
  To offer enhanced products and services to you.
                                                                                                                     1
  For joint marketing with other financial companies                                      Yes                    Yes
  For our affiliate’s everyday business purposes –                                        Yes                     No
  Information about your transactions and experiences.
  For our affiliate’s everyday business purposes –                                        No               Metro does not
  Information about your creditworthiness.                                                                       share
                                                                                                                     1
  For our affiliates to market to you                                                     Yes                    Yes
                                                                                              2                      1
  For non-affiliates to market to you                                                    Yes                     Yes
11-18

                                                                       PRIVACY NOTICE
  Who we are …
  Who is providing this                Metro Credit Union, a cooperative financial institution founded in 1926,
                                       headquartered in Chelsea, Massachusetts, servicing members in the
  notice?                              Massachusetts counties of Barnstable, Bristol, Essex, Middlesex, Norfolk,
                                       Plymouth, Suffolk, and Worcester and New Hampshire Counties of
                                       Hillsborough and Rockingham.
  What we do …
  How does Metro Credit               To protect your personal information from unauthorized access and use, we use
  Union protect my personal           security measures that are designed to comply with federal law. These measures
                                                                                                       3
  information?                        include computer safeguards and secured files and buildings .
                                      We collect your personal information, for example, when you:
                                            •    Open an account or deposit money
  How does Metro Credit                     •    Apply for a loan or pay your bills
  Union collect my personal                 •    Use your credit or debit card
  information?
                                      We also collect your personal information from others, such as credit bureaus,
                                      affiliates, or other companies.
                                      Federal law gives you the right to limit only
                                            •    Sharing for affiliates’ everyday business purposes – information about
                                                 your creditworthiness
  Why can’t I limit all                     •    Affiliates from using your information to market to you
  sharing?                                  •    Sharing for non-affiliates to market to you
                                      State law and individual companies may give you additional rights to limit
                                               4
                                      sharing .
  Definitions …
                                      Companies related by common ownership or control. They can be financial and
  Affiliates                          nonfinancial companies.
                                            •    Metro Insurance Advisors, LLC is an affiliate of Metro Credit Union.
                                      Companies not related by common ownership or control. They can be financial
                                      and nonfinancial companies.
  Non-affiliates
                                            •    Our non-affiliate partners include debit rewards processors and
                                                 associated merchants.
                                      A formal agreement between nonaffiliated financial companies that together
                                      market financial products or services to you.
  Joint Marketing
                                            •    Our joint marketing partners include credit card processors,
                                                 investment companies, and insurance companies.
  Notes
           Members may “opt-out” of sharing by contacting our member service center (877-MY-METRO).
           Non-Affiliate information sharing applies only to My Reward Checking accountholders.
      (3) Metro Credit Union has instituted programs to ensure the security and privacy of personal information with
           oversight from our management teams.
      (4) Please refer to the Massachusetts Office of Consumer Affairs & Business Regulation web site for more
           information: http://www.mass.gov/ocabr/data-privacy-and-security/.
11-18

ONLINE PRIVACY POLICY
In order to effectively deliver comprehensive online banking services, Metro must collect
personal information about members and others who visit and use its internet web site.
As with information we collect through other means, we use the information members
provide online to respond to member needs, service member accounts, and provide
members with information about other services Metro offers.
INFORMATION WE MAY COLLECT.
Metro may collect any personal information you share with Metro when you use Metro’s
website(s) to perform your banking on line, such as when you apply for a loan, pay bills,
make payments on a loan or a credit card, and when you use Metro’s website(s) to
inquire about Metro’s products and services, such as when you request information
about products and services, or answer an on-line survey.
Metro also collects certain non-personal information when you visit Metro’s website(s).
For example, our servers keep an activity log that tracks all visitors to the Metro Credit
Union website(s). The information in the activity log is anonymous and therefore does
not identify you individually. The anonymous information our server collects may include
among other data: your IP address, browser type, your registered domain or home
server, time of access, date of access, web page(s) visited, number of clicks, software
crash reports, session identification number, search terms, search results, access times
and referring website’s addresses.
This information is collected through use of cookies. A cookie is a small piece of
information that a website stores directly on the computer a member is using. Cookies
can contain a variety of information, from a simple count of how often a member visits a
website to information which allows customization of a website for member use. Metro
Credit Union uses cookies to gather data about the usage of our website. Anytime a
cookie is used, personal information is encrypted for our use only and is protected from
third party access. Under no circumstances can a website other than those from our
domain read or interact with the cookies created by our domain.
Google Analytics
Metro’s website uses Google Analytics, a web analytics service provided by Google.
Google Analytics uses cookies to collect anonymous traffic data to help us analyze how
users use the Site. The information generated by a cookie about your use of the Site
(including your IP address) will be transmitted to and stored by Google on servers in the
United States. Google will use this information for the purpose of evaluating your use of
the Site, compiling reports on Site activity for us and providing other services relating to
Site activity and internet usage. The data generated by Google Analytics is used solely
by Metro for the purposes of evaluating the demand for, and offering, its own services
and products.
Google may also transfer this information to third parties where required to do so by
law, or where such third parties process the information on Google’s behalf. By using
Rev. 10/15

the Site, you consent to the processing of data about you by Google in the manner and
for the purposes described in this Privacy Policy.
You may opt-out of Google Analytics for Display Advertising, customize Google Display
Network ads by clicking here. For more information about opting out, click here.
The data generated by Google Analytics is used solely by Metro for the purposes of
evaluating the demand for, and offering, its own services and products. Though this
data is processed and stored by Google or its third party affiliates, the data remains
Metro’s property, and neither Metro nor Google, nor third parties employed by Google,
may sell this data.
Third Party Links
Metro Credit Union provides links to business partner websites and to other resource
websites as a courtesy. A notification message appears as members click on our credit
union partner links to advise that they are leaving the Metro Credit Union website and
entering an external website outside of our domain. Users are also notified that at that
time, they may cancel this action and return to our website or continue to the external
site. A business partner website will be identified with our logo. In addition, Metro’s
website may direct you to social media sites, such as Facebook, Twitter and LinkedIn.
Metro may collect any personal information you share on these social networking sites.
Please remember that when a member leaves our site, our Privacy Policy is no longer
in effect. Once members visit another website, their web privacy and security is defined
by that website's own policies. This includes social media and networking sites where
Metro maintains an online presence. When accessing any third party content within, or
through, the Metro Credit Union website, we encourage members to review the privacy
policy and security offered on that site before providing any personal information. Metro
Credit Union does not guarantee or assume liability for any third party product or service
obtained through our website. Metro Credit Union does not represent either the third
party or the member if the two enter into a transaction. Please also remember that
social media and email are not secure methods of communicating with Metro.
Rev. 10/15
